thetechguys.com 2015-06-12

# KNOWHOW | Privacy & Cookies

##  Complete Cookie Knowhow

When you are browsing websites on the internet, many of these websites store tiny text files called cookies on your computer, to help track your use of the site and to personalise your journey around the website. These cookies can be stored so that if you return to a website, that website server can call the information from the cookies stored on your computer to tailor your experience of the site.

Knowhow.com is no different, we use cookies to help you shop our website more effectively and to place online orders - we do not store personally identifiable information in our cookie data. We also use some carefully selected 3rd party suppliers to enhance your online experience and they will place cookies on your computer for use on our website too.

Cookies are perfectly safe to be stored on your computer and almost all web browsers have cookie storing enabled as default. However, all browsers have the option of disabling cookies being stored on your computer if you wish to do this.

**Please be aware** that disabling cookies on your browser will reduce your ability to use Knowhow.com. We use cookies in various ways on our website that may stop the site from working fully when you disable them. This would also be a common experience of reduced functionality across many websites.

Learn how to change the cookie settings for your browser on our Knowhow to Control Cookies link.

Recent legislation from the European Union has meant that websites must provide clear information about their use of cookies to their customers, something we at Knowhow fully support. We want to ensure that you, as our valued customer, are fully aware of the use of cookies on our website, and we are proud of our reputation as a transparent and honest retailer that you can trust.

##  Knowhow we use Cookies...

We want to make sure you are fully aware of the cookies we use and what they do when you are shopping on Knowhow.com.

Here is a full guide to our cookies explaining the name of the cookie as it would appear on your computer, a description of what the cookie is used for and a rating from our technical teams on level of information held:

Cookie Name |  Description of the cookie and its purpose  
---|---  
Google Analytics (_utXX) |  We use Google Analytics to help provide us data about the way our customers use our websites to improve your experience. Google Analytics cookies record visitors, city locations, browser type and site journey. Google Analytics cookies do not record personal information. For a full description of Google's use of cookies please visit:

<http://code.google.com/apis/analytics/docs/concepts/gaConceptsCookies.html>  
  
Omniture (s_vi) |  This is a cookie we deploy for our analytics through Adobe Omniture. The cookie deploys on your computer and generates a unique ID for us to measure visits and site journeys through Knowhow.com. This cookie does not collect any personally identifiable information.

Omniture's privacy statement can be found at the below address:

<http://www.omniture.com/en/privacy/policy>  
  
Google Services (NID, PREF, HSID, SSID, APISID, SAPISID, SID) |  Google services such as Google Maps, Google+ and Google Accounts deploy cookies to measure usage and interaction with their services on our site where we deploy some of their services such as Google Maps. These cookies do not contain any personally identifiable information and are used to measure usage and enhance personal experience of the tools. The cookies are not permanent and more details on the Google usage of cookies can be found below:

<http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>  
  
Knowhow (knowhow_ratedPages) |  This is a cookie we deploy from Knowhow.com for use when a visitor chooses to rate one of our articles in the knowledge bank. The cookie is stored on your machine to recall your rating of an article. It contains no personally identifiable information.  
Knowhow (sitemap-collapsed) |  This is a cookie we deploy from Knowhow.com that remembers the state of certain interactive features of the website during your session such as the expanded services menu in the footer. It only persists during the duration of your session and contains no personally identifiable information.  
  
These are all the cookies currently used by our website and our approved suppliers. Hopefully it is clear that all of our cookies are used ultimately to improve the journey for our customers online or to help us present a better website experience online.

If you feel you would like to change your personal interaction with cookies, you can adjust storage of cookies settings through your web browser by checking out our Knowhow to Control Cookies link.

**Please be aware** disabling cookies will severely limit your ability to use Knowhow.com and disable features of many websites across the internet.

Back to top

##  Knowhow to Control Cookies

Cookies should be enabled by default on your browser, so if you have not changed your settings you should expect to be accepting cookies from websites.

Cookies being disabled will limit your experience of Knowhow.com and many other websites online. Remember, cookies are not harmful to your computer and our cookies on Knowhow.com do not contain any personally identifiable information. If you wish to change your cookie settings we have provided a guide below for you. **Please remember** , if you do disable your cookies, you can allow cookies from certain approved websites, by adding the website homepage to your exceptions list.

First, find out what your default web browser is on your machine, or the browser you use most often to access the internet. To work out what browser you are using, simply open the internet as usual, and then follow the steps below:

**PC Users**

On the tool bar at the top of your browser click 'Help' and choose the 'About' option from the drop down. This will tell you the browser type and version.

**Mac Users**

Open the internet as usual and once open, click on the Apple icon in the top left corner and choose the 'About' option. This will again tell you the browser type and version.

Once you know the browser you are using you can find the cookie settings using the guide below relevant for your browser:

|  **Checking your settings in Internet Explorer 8 and earlier versions**  
1\. Locate the 'Tools' tab on the menu areas of your browser. Click on this.  
2\. There is an option called 'Internet Options' on the list, select this option.  
3\. This should open a pop up box with lots of tabbed options. Select the 'Privacy' tab from the list.  
4\. Internet Explorer has a high, medium, low auto-adjust system for internet content handling. You can configure your own settings by clicking the advanced tab and ticking the 'Override automatic cookie handling'  
5\. Settings above Medium will disable cookies, Medium or below will enable cookies  
---|---  
|  **Checking your settings in Mozilla Firefox**  
1\. Locate the 'Tools' tab on the menu areas of your browser. Click on this.  
2\. From the list of options on the drop down menu, click on 'Options'  
3\. There should be a pop up window appear with tabs along the top. Find the 'Privacy' tab and select this.  
4\. You should now have some options for 'Tracking' and 'History'. Under the 'History' drop down menu, select 'Use customer settings for history' if you wish to adjust your cookie settings.  
|  **Checking your settings in Google Chrome**  
1\. Look for the spanner icon in Chrome  and click on this  
2\. From this menu, select settings...  
3\. Within settings you will see tabs on the left hand side. Select the tab called 'Under the Hood'  
4\. When this page loads you will see a tab at the top called 'Content Settings' - select this  
5\. This brings up your content controls including cookie permissions - select the option you feel most comfortable with  
|  **Checking your settings in Safari**  
1\. Locate the Cog icon at the top of your browser  and click on this.  
2\. From the list of options select 'Preferences'  
3\. This should open a pop up window with several tabs along the top. From this list select the 'Privacy' option.  
4\. This will open the tab page that allows you to control the cookie settings on your browser.  
|  **Checking your settings in Opera**  
1\. Click the Opera file icon in the top left hand corner of your browser.  
2\. From the drop down list of options, highlight 'Settings' and then scroll across and select 'Preferences'.  
3\. This should open a pop up window with tabs along the top. Choose the 'Advanced' tab.  
4\. This shows you the advanced options. On the left hand side there is an option called 'Cookies' - click on this option.  
5\. This presents the cookie options for your use on this browser.  
  |  **If you have another browser...**

Please check the help settings within your browser or use a search engine to find answers on the best way to enable or disable cookies in your chosen browser. Please remember we are not responsible for the content on external websites.

**If you want more information...**

You can visit the following website for an in-depth guide to cookies and how to control, delete and understand them. They even have a great recipe on there for cookies of the edible variety - yum!

<http://www.aboutcookies.org/>  
  
Back to top

##  Privacy on Knowhow

####  WHO WE ARE

In this Privacy Policy references to ‘we’ and ‘us’s are to DSG Retail Limited trading as Knowhow, Currys, PC World and Partmaster Direct, company number 504877, registered office Maylands Avenue, Hemel Hempstead, Hertfordshire HP2 7TG.

####  WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW

The information we collect via this website may include:

(1) Any personal details you type in and submit, such as name, address, email address, etc.

(2) Data which allows us to recognise you, your preferences and how you use this website. This saves you from re-entering information when you return to the site. This data is collected by cookies from your navigation around the site. A cookie is a small amount of data which we send to your computer. The data is then stored on your browser or hard disk. Most web browsers can be set to prevent you from receiving new cookies, notify you before accepting cookies or disable cookies altogether. Details about this can normally be found in the Help facility provided with your browser. If you disable cookies, you will not be able to receive personalised facilities and your progress to check out may take longer. The cookies store information only for as long as you are viewing the website. If you do not want your visits to our website to be monitored in this way you can find out more about removing cookies by [clicking here](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

(3) Your IP address (this is your computer’s individual identification number) which is automatically logged by our web server. This is used to note your interest in our website.

(4) Your preferences and use of email updates, recorded by emails we send you (if you select to receive email updates on products and offers).

####  WHAT DO WE DO WITH YOUR INFORMATION

Any personal information we collect from you will be used in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and other applicable laws. The details we collect will be used:

(1) to process your order, to process any application for finance or a mobile phone contract etc., to maintain guarantee records and to provide after-sales service (we may pass your details to another organisation to supply/deliver products or services you have purchased and/or to provide after-sales service).

(2) to carry out security checks (this may involve passing your details to our Identity Verification partner, currently 192.com, who will check details we give them against public and private databases - this helps to protect you and us from fraudulent transactions); and

(3) to comply with legal requirements (e.g. if you buy a TV or similar, we are obliged to pass your details to the TV licensing authority).

We are a subsidiary of Dixons Carphone plc and we may need to pass the information we collect to other companies within our group for administrative purposes. We may use third parties to carry out certain activities, such as processing and sorting data, monitoring how customers use our site and issuing our emails for us.

We would also like to inform you of various promotions, goods and services that may be of interest to you. These would come from any of our chains (or those of the Dixons Carphone plc Group), including Currys, PC World, Carphone Warehouse and Partmaster Direct, from our affiliates, or from carefully selected third parties. You may be contacted by post, email, telephone, SMS or such other means as we regard as appropriate, including new technology. If you wish to receive these communications, please tick the ‘Yes’ box when entering your personal details. You may unsubscribe at a later date, if you wish - ‘Your rights’ section below.

####  YOUR RIGHTS

(1) You can ask us to update your personal information by emailing precise details of your request to [customerservices@dixonsretail.com.](mailto:customerservices@dixonsretail.com)

(2) You can ask us not to send you future marketing communications. To do this, simply click [this link](https://dixonsregistration.co.uk/permoptout/?referrer=6) and submit your details.

We will then suppress your data from all direct marketing, although we will still keep it for processing your order and fulfilling customer service and after sale obligations. Alternatively, you can post your request to the address in (3) below.

(3) You also have the right to request a copy of any personal information we hold about you. To do this, simply write to us at the following address.  Please enclose a cheque for £10 payable to DSG Retail Limited to cover our administration costs and proof of ID such as a copy of your driving licence or a recent utility bill:

Subject Access Request  
Legal Services  
DSG Retail Limited  
Maylands Avenue  
Hemel Hempstead  
Hertfordshire  
HP2 7TG

**OTHER WEBSITES**

This privacy policy only covers this website. Any other websites which may be linked to by our website are subject to their own policy, which may differ from ours.

****Back to top****
